builddirect.com 2019-07-16

# BuildDirect® - Flooring, Decking, Siding, Roofing, and More

Last updated January 29, 2019

### APPLICATION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY

BuildDirect.com Technologies Inc. (“BuildDirect” or “we” or “us”) respects the privacy of its customers, suppliers and visitors. BuildDirect believes in protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy outlines how we obtain, share and collect personal information. By using [www.builddirect.com](https://www.builddirect.com/) (the “Site”) and/or providing personal information to us, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. The purpose of collecting personal information from you is to improve your experience using BuildDirect and to provide you with additional information on our products, services and promotions. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies, other entities or websites that BuildDirect does not manage or control. It applies to interaction you have with the Site or with a member of the BuildDirect Team. This Privacy Policy also covers our treatment of any personal information shared with us by third parties.

### THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

You can visit the Site and its sub-domains without registering for membership or subscribing to any communications. The Site contains links to third-party sites, which are not governed by this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of third-party sites or services to which links or access are provided through the Site. We encourage you to learn about third parties’ privacy and security policies before providing them with information.

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Personal information means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. We collect personal information such as your name, your home address, your financial information and your personal preferences as part of conducting transactions with you and when you visit the Site. If you choose to withhold any personal information requested by us, it may not be possible for you to gain access to certain parts of the Site or services.

Your contact information is your name associated with your business address, business email, business telephone, business fax and other business contact information.

## TYPES OF PERSONAL INFORMATION BUILDDIRECT COLLECTS FROM YOU

The legal bases for our processing of personal information are primarily that the processing is necessary for providing the Site or services and that the processing is carried out in our legitimate interests, which are further explained below. We may also process personal information upon your consent, asking for such consent as appropriate.

### Payment and Shipping Information

When you purchase a product on the Site we collect your financial information to process the order. We may also collect your billing and shipping addresses for the purposes of fulfilling your transaction. We may also collect your order history and feedback in relation to your experience with BuildDirect.

### Demographic Information

We may collect information like your age and gender. We may collect information about the products you like or the reviews and comments you post online.

### Location Information

We may collect information from your IP address in relation to your location. The data is used to best match our products to the areas of demand.

### Employment Related Information

We may collect information you give us in contemplation of an employment opportunity with BuildDirect.

### Browsing Information

We may track the pages you visit or the path you took to land on the Site page and what website you visit when you leave us. We collect this information using tracking tools. For more information on these tracking tools please check your browsers Privacy Preferences or similar pages.

## HOW BUILDDIRECT COLLECTS PERSONAL INFORMATION FROM YOU

### We gather information you give us directly.

There are many ways you give information to us directly and includes but is not limited to, the following:

  * Information you input into the Site in connection with purchasing the products advertised;
  * Telephone conversations;
  * Online chat interaction;
  * Email communications;
  * Face to face meetings;
  * Social Media Interaction through third party websites such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram and YouTube;
  * Viewing our online advertisements or emails;
  * Resumes, cover letters and pre-screening calls in connection with an employment opportunity at BuildDirect; and
  * All other communications with members of the BuildDirect team.

### HOW BUILDDIRECT COLLECTS NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION

### We gather non-personal information from you indirectly

This is mainly through your browser using tracking tools like behavior tracking, pixel tags and cookies. Third parties such as delivery companies may also give us updated information in connection with your order.

### Behavior Tracking

BuildDirect uses cookies to store information about your web site visit, activities, and preferences. A cookie is a small amount of text that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Most modern browsers automatically accept the placement of the cookie on your computer’s hard drive. If you would prefer to prevent your computer from accepting cookies, you can disable cookies from your browser; however, you may not be able to access certain features of the Site.

Like most other commercial websites, the Site may monitor traffic patterns, site usage and related sites. We may automatically (i.e., not via registration) collect or compile certain information when you access the Site. Examples of this type of information include the aggregate and unique number of visitors to the Site, the dates and times of visits to the Site, IP addresses and the domains, cities and countries of visitors, the pages of the Site visited and the content accessed, the type and version of the browser and operating system used to access the Site, search engine and search terms used within the Site or to visit the Site, referring sites, and HTTP errors generated.

We use this information in order to assess the usage of our the Site and our marketing efforts, to send you tailored browser notifications with news and offers (with your consent), to optimize the Site, and to monitor the Site’s performance. We may provide such information to the Site contractors for these purposes. We also may use a web analytics service or services on some pages to improve web design and usability. This may involve recording mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as any text you type on the Site. BuildDirect does not track your browsing habits across websites which do not use the same services.

We work with ad content generation third parties such as Facebook, and Google Analytics to display ads to the Site prospects, on our behalf, across the Internet. They collect information about your visits to the Site, and your interaction with our products and services. The anonymous information is collected through the use of cookies and pixel tags. We use cookies and other techniques to track your interactions with the Site; some of these technologies keep tracking your behavior when cookies are disabled. Pixel tags are industry standard technology used by most major web sites. We use the Site behaviour information for marketing purposes, system administration and also to identify problems and improve service.

  * To review the privacy policy and opt out of Google Analytics program, visit the opt out of behavioral advertising link <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en>
  * To review the Facebook privacy policy on custom audience ads and opt out from the program visit <https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/>
  * To review the Rubicon privacy policy and opt out of ads, visit <https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/>
  * To review the Steelhouse privacy policy and opt out of ads, visit <http://www.steelhouse.com/opt-out/>
  * To review the Quantcast privacy policy and opt out of ads, visit<https://www.quantcast.com/company/opt-out>
  * To review the Adobe Analytics Privacy Policy and opt out visit <https://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html>
  * To review the Intellimize privacy policy and to opt out of ads please visit <https://www.intellimize.com/privacy/>
  * To review the Pinterest privacy policy and to opt out of ads please visit <https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy>
  * To review the Instagram privacy policy and to opt out of ads please visit <https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875>

### Do not track signals

The Site does not respond to Do-Not-Track signals from the browser. Instead, you can download and install browser plugins to automatically block tracking technologies.

## HOW BUILDDIRECT USES YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

### We take steps designed to ensure that only those employees who need access to your personal information to fulfil their employment duties will have access to it. BuildDirect may collect and use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to contact you in relation to your online visit and/or telephone call with our Sales Team, to fulfill orders and sales, and to follow up with you in relation to your order;
  * to match your location with the products you have selected to ensure proper and expeditious delivery to you;
  * to communicate with you about your inquiry, your account, your shopping cart or our relationship;
  * to look at website trends and customer interests;
  * to administer and build your BuildDirect account;
  * to market new services and products that we believe will be of interest to you (including by email, SMS text message and push notifications to your browser or mobile app);
  * to collect a debt owed to BuildDirect or its agents; or to pay a debt owed by BuildDirect;
  * to help us make credit decisions about clients and check the identity of new clients to prevent fraud and money laundering;
  * to help us make a decision with respect to employment or an appointment with BuildDirect;
  * to identify you if you visit our office premises;
  * as required or authorized by law; and
  * for other uses we may disclose to you from time to time.

## DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Information about our customers is an important aspect of our business. BuildDirect undertakes to treat this information with integrity and does not and will not sell, or disclose your information unless for business purposes or as required by law. We will implement appropriate technical and organizational measures (including contractual or other arrangements) to protect information disclosed to third parties, who perform services on our behalf. These third parties include, but are not limited to, delivery service providers who ship and deliver your online orders and technology service providers who provide services in support of BuildDirect’s business.

Your personal information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage third party service providers. By using the Site and/or providing personal information to us, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside your country of residence, which may have different data protection rules than in your country. While such information is outside of Canada, it is subject to the laws of the country in which it is held, and may be subject to disclosure to the governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of such other country, pursuant to the laws of such country. However, our practices regarding your personal information will at all times continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy and, if applicable, we will comply with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal information from the EU/EEA to third country.

### BuildDirect may disclose your personal information:

  * when the services we are providing to you require us to give information to third parties, for example: providing government-assigned identification numbers to customs brokers or other third parties responsible for processing customs clearance for shipments;
  * if we engage a third party to provide services to us (such as payroll processing for employees, computer back-up services, archival file storage, customer relationship management, advertising distribution, behavior tracking, marketing animation, delivering orders, processing credit card payments ) and the third party is bound by confidentiality obligations;
  * with vendors and manufacturers to respond to your feedback, comments, reviews and/or claims;
  * where it is necessary to collect a debt owed to BuildDirect or its agents, or to pay a debt owed by BuildDirect;
  * as part of an investigation to protect us if we suspect fraud;
  * to respond to an emergency where the health or safety of any individual is reasonably believed to be threatened;
  * if the information is already publicly known;
  * when we are required or authorized by law to do so; and/or
  * in other circumstances where you have consented to the disclosure.

### We may collect, use and disclose information without your consent when we are required or authorized by law to do so.

## HOW BUILDDIRECT SECURES YOUR INFORMATION 

BuildDirect takes all reasonable steps to ensure that your information is kept safe from loss, unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.

### The steps we take to protect your information include:

  * Premises security
  * Restricted file access to your information
  * Deploying technological safeguards like encryption, access control, and firewalls to protect against hacking or unauthorized computer access
  * Use of secure socket layer (SSL) to encrypt credit card transactions 
  * Use of authentication to access your account
  * Periodical reviewing of security measures.

Beyond the implementation of conscientious information protection best practices, you should be aware that Internet communications are not absolutely private or confidential. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any personal information in your possession. If you believe your personal information has been compromised, please contact us as set forth in the “Governance” section of this Privacy Policy. If we learn of a security systems breach, we will inform you and the authorities of the occurrence of the breach in accordance with applicable law. Note that certain parts of the Site services including but not limited to blog and learning center posts are public and your comments may be viewed by other users and Site visitors.

## RIGHTS REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

### Withdrawing Consent 

Individuals have the right to withdraw their consent to the collection, use, or disclosure of information at any time, except where that withdrawal would frustrate the performance of a legal obligation by BuildDirect.

### Accessing or Correcting Your Information

Individuals have the right to know what Information BuildDirect has collected about them, how that information is being used and to whom it has been disclosed, as well as to verify and amend that information if it is incorrect. If necessary, BuildDirect will correct the information if requested to do so.

### Removing Information stored by BuildDirect

Subject to applicable laws, upon reasonable written notice given to BuildDirect, all information held by BuildDirect that is identifiable to that individual will be removed from our records and confirmation of that removal will be provided to the individual. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if you withdraw consent, BuildDirect nonetheless reserves the right to retain, collect, use and disclose information without your consent where we are permitted and/or required by law to do so.

### Other Provisions Under the GDPR

Under the GDPR, you may be entitled to additional rights, including: (i) the right to object to unlawful data processing, under certain conditions; (ii) the right to demand that we restrict processing of your personal information, under certain conditions, if you believe we have exceeded the legitimate basis for processing, processing is no longer necessary, or believe your personal information is inaccurate; (iii) the right to data portability of personal information that you provided us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format, under certain conditions; (iv) the right object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you, under certain conditions; (v) the right to lodge a complaint with data protection authorities. If you want to learn more about your rights under the GDPR, you can visit the European Commission’s page on Data Protection at: [ http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/index_en.htm.](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/index_en.htm)

### Unsubscribing from Marketing and Promotional Material

From time to time, BuildDirect may engage a third-party marketing agency to distribute advertisements to consumers who have expressed an interest in receiving such material. For this purpose, the marketing agency may use its own distribution list. This list is not under BuildDirect’s control and may not be shared with BuildDirect. In relaying an opt-out request to a third-party marketing agency, BuildDirect therefore accepts no responsibility for any consequences to the requester arising from the actions of the agency. 

You may wish to opt out of receiving certain information or marketing and promotional material distributed directly by BuildDirect. You may do so by selecting the opt-out or unsubscribe feature in our online communications including our online newsletter and product updates.

We may also obtain your consent to send push notifications to your browser. These notifications will contain news and offers from BuildDirect.com and may be tailored based on your interests and the areas of the Site you have visited. You can stop receiving these notifications at any time by changing your browser settings.

  * If you are using **Chrome** , [click here](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/3220216?hl=en) for instructions on how to change your notification settings and unsubscribe from browser push notifications.
  * If you are using **Firefox** , [click here](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/push-notifications-firefox) for instructions on how to change your notification settings and unsubscribe from browser push notifications
  * If you are using **Safari** , [click here](https://appsliced.co/ask/how-do-i-disable-website-notifications-in-safari) for instructions on how to change your notification settings and unsubscribe from browser push notifications

For more information or to initiate any of the above requests, contact us as set forth in the “Governance” section of this Privacy Policy. When contacting us please provide sufficient detail to enable BuildDirect to confirm your identity. BuildDirect may contact you directly to confirm your identity. Upon receiving this request, BuildDirect will respond to your query as soon as possible and information will normally be released to the requester within 30 days, subject to applicable laws.

## CHILDREN

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16 without obtaining parental consent. If you are under 16 years of age, then please do not use the Site and/or provide personal information at any time or in any manner. If we learn that personal information has been collected from persons under 16 years of age and without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under 16 years of age has provided personal information, then you may alert us as set forth in the “Governance” section of this Privacy Policy and request that we delete that child’s personal information from our systems.

## RETENTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will only keep your personal information for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the relevant purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and in order to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations. If you would like further information regarding the periods for which your personal information will be kept, please contact us as set forth in the “Governance” section of this Privacy Policy.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Since BuildDirect regularly reviews all of its policies and procedures, we may change this Privacy Policy, in its sole discretion, from time to time according to relevant laws and policies. Any changes or modification will be effective upon posting of the revisions to the Site. Your continued use of this Site and/or BuildDirect’s services following the posting of any changes or modifications to the Site will constitute your acceptance of such changes or modifications to this Privacy Policy. You should therefore frequently review this Privacy Policy.

## GOVERNANCE

This Privacy Policy will be governed by the laws of the Province of British Columbia and the laws of Canada applicable therein, excluding any conflict of rules that would apply to another body of law. This Privacy Policy constitutes and contains the entire agreement between you and BuildDirect with respect to its subject matter and supersedes any prior oral or written agreements.

If any provision of this Privacy Policy is held to be illegal or unenforceable, that provision will be limited or eliminated to the minimum extent necessary so that this Privacy Policy will otherwise remain in full force and effect and enforceable.

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or your personal information and/or if you wish to (a) make an access or correction request, (b) exercise any applicable rights, (c) make a complaint, or (d) obtain information about our policies and practices with respect to any service providers outside Canada, our Privacy Officer can be reached by mail or email using the following contact information:

BuildDirect.com Technologies Inc.  
Privacy Officer  
1900, 401 West Georgia  
Vancouver, British Columbia, V6B5A1
